SHANTANU TRYAMBAKRAO JAYALE

Flat No: 201, "Gulmohor", Plot No. 137, Nagarvikas Housing

Cooperative Society, Near SBI ATM, Manish Nagar,

Somalwada, Nagur (MH).

PIN: 440015

Contact No.: +91-9403395370 / +97-7020514177

Email: jayaleshantanu10@gmail.com / shantanu_jayale@yahoo.co.in

PROFILE:

Agriculture post graduate with specialization in Plant Pathology and over a **7 years** of experience in Research, Development, Field & Lab Diagnosis of Plant Diseases, Data Management, Crop Advisories, SOP's etc. Currently working as "Scientist - B" at Cropdata Technology Pvt. Ltd., Nagpur. Aspire to be an important part of the organization and again experience in the field of agriculture merchandise. Hard-working achiever, dedicated to ontime delivery and enthusiastic team player. To be associated with a progressive organization that gives scope to update my practical knowledge and skill in accordance with contemporary trends.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

- ❖ M. Sc. Plant Pathology from Jawaharlal Neharu Krishi Vishwa Vidyalaya, Jabalpur in 2014 with 69.60% Marks.
- ❖ B. Sc. Horticulture from Dr. Panjabrao Deshmukh Krishi Vidyapeeth, Akola in 2009with 68.00 % Marks.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

8 April 2019 to Till Date: Working as "Scientist B" at Cropdata Technology Pvt. Ltd., Nagpur.

Job responsibilities:

- Collection and compilation of the available data related to diseases of various agricultural crops grown in different Agro-climatic zone of the country.
- Identification of diseased plant samples at central laboratory, collected from different locations of the country.
- Engage with development team involved in development of Disease Prediction Model, Yield Prediction Model, Weather Forecasting Model along with Disease Development, etc.
- Establishment of Central and Regional Laboratories.
- Preparation of training modules for regional / ground staff.
- Training of regional staff on disease identification.
- Reporting Manager team handling of more than 30 Field staff.

11 Sept 2018 to 31 March 2019 (6 Months): Worked as "**Agri Business Expert**" at Convergence of Agricultural Interventions in Maharashtra (CAIM) at District Programme Management Team, Dist: Wardha.

Job responsibilities:

- Along with the NGOs and private sector players, initiate actions to empowering the rural women to participate in markets effectively by increasing their awareness about the functions of markets and prices, the importance of quality and standards, increasing their participating in decision-making and negotiating through training;
- Initiate actions to promote producer groups or companies to increase their bargaining power in the market place and to gain the benefits of market institutions, such as warehouse receipt systems and commodity exchanges; ensure that this is underpinned in training in the potential benefits of forming such groups;
- Ensure that the SHGs, JLGs and CMRCs have a presence on local and regional fora associated with marketing improvements.
- Arrange facilities to improve the ability of SHGs, JLGS and CMRCs to overcome their cash constraints through linkages with banks and market institutions.
- Create and strengthen discussion between the private sector and SHGs, JLGs and CMRCs for enhancing the market environment, particularly with regard to prices and quality.
- Identify viable and technically feasible and financially viable sub-projects that are linked to markets and can be undertaken by the target group HHs in particular the SHGs, JLGs and CMRCs and also explore the funding and financing possibilities including convergence.
- Scout for PPP arrangements for the sub-projects such as contract farming, organic farming, milk production and collection centers, grain storage and ware houses etc.
- Identify micro-enterprises that have market and production potential and develop viable models for support and financing.
- Arrange training for the SHGs, JLGs and CMRC staff regarding quality and thereby ensuring better prices; and Facilitate investment in milling and processing units for primary processing within villages to make the task of milling more convenient for women by arranging medium term credit and organizing JLGs and SHGs.
- Prepare quarterly and annual reports based on the MIS data and field visits and also undertake problem specific field visits to the operating SHGs, JLGs and CMRCs and provide guidance to improving their performance and operations.
- Carry out specific market and commodity analysis to bring improvement in marketing and ensure better returns to the SHGs and in this respect, establish linkage with the private sector players and draw specific plans for development.

27 Sep 2016 to 19 July 2018 (1 yr 8 months): Worked as **Asst. Prof.** at Smt. Anusayabai Meghe College of Agriculture, Bhugaon, Dist: Wardha (Maharashtra)

Job responsibilities:

- Area Dist. Wardha, Maharashtra.
- Responsible for establishment of lab & field development.
- Responsible for teaching of various courses (Plant Pathology & Microbiology) to B.Sc. Ag students.
- Developing and maintaining effective relationships with the scientific students, community and the local agricultural authorities.

1 September 2015 to 31 March 2016 (7 months): Worked as Senior Research Fellow in the OPMAS project entitled, "Online Pest Monitoring and Advisory Services".

Job responsibilities:

- Worked as a Co- Investigator in AICRP, SAU and National Centre for Integrated Pest Management, New Delhi.
- Prepare experimental layouts for conducting trials.
- Technical observations of trials.
- Compilation and statistical analysis of data its interpretation.
- Preparation of reports.
- Demonstration of Integrated Pest Management practices.
- Involved in Extension activities like Shivar Pheri, Agrotech, Field Day's organized by Dr. PDK, Akola and deliver lecture to farmers regarding Cotton cultivation, Disease & Pest Management.

6 April 2015 to 30 Aug 2015 (4 months 24 days): Worked as Senior Research Fellow in the National Food Security Mission project entitled, "Insecticide Resistance Management & High Density Planting System in Cotton".

Job responsibilities:

- Worked as a Co- Investigator in AICRP, SAU and Central Institute for Cotton Research, Nagpur.
- Prepare experimental layouts for conducting trials on Insecticide Resistance Management & High Density Planting System in cotton.
- Distribution of seed among selected farmers.
- Technical observations of trials.
- Compilation and statistical analysis of data its interpretation.
- Preparation of reports.
- Demonstration of Integrated Pest Management practices to farmers.
- Involved in Extension activities like Shivar Pheri, Agrotech, Field Day's organized by Dr. PDKV, Akola and deliver lecture to farmers regarding Cotton cultivation,
 Disease & Pest Management.

27 October 2014 to 31 March 2015 (5 months 4 days): Worked as Senior Research Fellow in the National Food Security Mission project entitled, "Insecticide Resistance Management & High Density Planting System in cotton".

Job responsibilities:

- Working as a Co- Investigator in AICRP, SAU and Central Institute for Cotton Research, Nagpur.
- Prepare experimental layouts for conducting trials on Insecticide Resistance Management & High Density Planting System in cotton.
- Distribution of seed among selected farmers in Akola, Buldhana & Washim district of Maharashtra.
- Technical observations of trials and data collection.
- Compilation and statistical analysis of data its interpretation.
- Preparation of reports.
- Demonstration of Integrated Pest Management practices to farmers.
- Involved in Extension activities like Shivar Pheri, Agrotech, Field Day's organized by Dr. PDKV, Akola and deliver lecture to farmers regarding Cotton cultivation, Disease & Pest Management.

28 June 2013 to 30 August 2014 (1 yr 2 months): Worked as **Asst. Prof.** at Smt. Vasudhatai Deshmukh College of Agriculture, Talegaon Dashasar, Dis: Amravati.

- Responsible for establishment of lab & field development.
- Responsible for teaching of various courses (Plant Pathology & Microbiology) to B.Sc. Ag students.
- Developing and maintaining effective relationships with the scientific students, community and the local agricultural authorities.

Worked for a project during the M.Sc. at department of Plant Pathology, JNKVV, Jabalpur (MP) and submitted the thesis entitled "Studies on collar rot of Chickpea caused by *Sclerotium rolfsii* Sacc." from 2011-2013.

- Confirmation of pathogenecity of S. rolfsii.
- To study the effect of various parameters.
- To work out the economics of the treatment.

Practical Knowledge:

- Initiation and design of Plant Pathology experiments, experimental field designs.
- Data collection, analysis, interpretation and report writing.
- Field & Lab diagnosis of Plant Diseases, Plant Pathogens.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

- Sex & Marital Status: Male, Married
- Age & DOB: 32 years, 27th April 1986.
- Nationality / Citizen: Indian.
- Relocate: Willingness both Domestic and International.
- Languages known: English, Hindi and Marathi.
- Permanent address At. Po. Akoli Jahangir, Tal: Akot, Dist: AkolaMaharashtra -

Mob. 9403395370 / 7020514177

Date: 24/09/2020

(Shantanu Tryambakrao Jayale)